let's look at the solution to our
address translation quiz we have a
16-bit virtual address space and a four
entry page table that means that the
most significant two bits of the 16-bit
address are the page number the
remaining 14 bits are going to be the
page offset so this 16-bit address can
be written like this in binary F 0 F 0
the most significant two bits are really
the page number which corresponds to
this entry in the page table because
this is 3 so we need to look at this
entry in the page table in this
particular address we have 0 0 1 F these
two bits correspond to this entry in the
page table so now we can write out the
physical address that corresponds to
this virtual address it is going to
contain the frame number from entry
number 3 in the page table which is
going to be 1/7 concatenated with the
page offset which is going to be 1 1 etc
and we can now write it out it's going
to be 0 F 0 F 0 and then we have F and
this is 5 it's a 20-bit address so it
will have 5 hex digits similarly here we
are looking at entry number 0 here so
it's going to be 1 F followed by the
page offset so it's going to have 0 0
and then the remaining digits are going
to be the same so it's going to have F 1
0 and then C 7 C because it's 1 1 0 0
and 7 because it's 0 1 1 1 so this is
the physical address for this particular
virtual address